pitb.gov.pk 2010-05-19

# PITB Privacy Policy

|  |  |  |   
  
---|---|---  
|  |   
  
---|---  
|  |  |  |  |  |  | 

PITB PRIVACY POLICY   

The Punjab Information Technology Board (PITB) is committed to protecting privacy of the users (the Users) of www.pitb.gov.pk (the Website) and to making the Users’ online experience secure, comfortable, valuable and pleasant. 

PITB does not collect any information about the Users unless they choose to provide that information. PITB may share necessary data with other Government bodies, agencies and departments. However, information collected by PITB is used only for use of PITB, official purposes, internal reviews, improvement of the content of the Website, customization of the content and layout of the Website and to contact the Users. PITB does not use, share or pass on the Users information for commercial purposes. 

|    
  
  |   
---|---|---|---  
|  |  All record keepers face the possibility of disclosure of their records in some civil, criminal, or administrative matter. PITB could be required to disclose personal information in response to valid legal processes such as applicable laws, search warrant, subpoena, or court order. Disclosures may also be necessary to protect PITB’s legal rights or during emergencies if physical safety is believed to be at risk.  |   
---|---|---  
|  | 

What Information About Users Does PITB Collect?

PITB considers any information that could reasonably be used to identify the Users as "personally identifying information." PITB does not retain personally identifiable information about the Users when they visit the Website unless they choose to provide such information to PITB (i.e. sending an e-mail, registering as the User, participating in a survey, responding to a feedback or "contact us" form, etc.)  |   
---|---|---  
|  |  PITB, Government Departments, Bodies, Agencies and Organizations may request personally identifiable information from the Users in order to provide requested services however, such information is handled as in the case of an in-person visit to that same Body, Department, Agency or Organization.  |   
---|---|---  
|  | 

E-Mail Communications and Web Forms

If the Users send PITB an electronic mail message with a question or comment that contains personally identifying information, or fill out a form that e-mails PITB information, PITB will use this personally identifying information only to respond to the Users’ requests. PITB may redirect your message to another government agency or person who is in a better position to respond to the Users’ queries or comments.  |   
---|---|---  
|  |  All e-mail messages received contain the e-mail addresses of persons who voluntarily communicated with or requested information from PITB. The Users’ e-mail addresses are not sold, leased or shared with any non-governmental or commercial entities without the Users’ consent. When the Users give their e-mail addresses to PITB for purposes of communicating with or requesting information, that communication becomes part of the public record and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by law.  |   
---|---|---  
|  |  Information submitted via e-mail or web forms may be at risk of being intercepted, read or modified. The Users are advised not to pass on any personal and confidential information such as security passwords and credit card numbers while using the Website unless specifically required by an authorized person. PITB shall not be liable for any misuse or loss of any such information.  |   
---|---|---  
|  | 

Web Cookies

A Cookie is a small file stored on computer by the web browser when using some Internet sites. Cookies can also store personal information such as name, e-mail address, home or work address, or telephone number. Persistent Cookies can use this type of personal information to identify a user whenever that user accesses a web site. Sessional Cookies are used to help you move around a web site and do not store personal information.

The Website does not use Persistent Cookies or Sessional Cookies. 

|   
---|---|---  
|  | 

Security Measures

PITB takes very seriously the integrity of the information and systems that PITB maintains. Hence, appropriate safeguards have been employed to ensure that any personal information is secure from destruction, corruption, unauthorized access and breach of confidentiality. 

Several steps have been taken to safeguard the integrity of PITB’s computer systems and networks. These steps include, but are not limited to individual authentication, the security of transmitted data, security monitoring, auditing and encryption of information. 

|   
---|---|---  
|  | 

Is User Information Shared? 

Except as provided by applicable laws, PITB does not collect, use or disclose the Users information without the Users’ knowledge and approval. PITB does not share the Users’ information with third parties unless PITB has informed the Users about the disclosures or have prior consent.  |   
---|---|---  
|  | 

Can I Access and Correct My Personal Information? 

The Users concerned about information contained in their personal records should contact the custodian of the record, which typically is the governmental entity that collects and maintains the information. The Users may request changes or annotate their personal information if they believe it to be inaccurate by submitting a written request describing the error. 

PITB does not collect any personally identifiable information other than what the Users provide. The automatic data recorded is not matched with any of that personally identifiable information, therefore information cannot be provided about the Users’ visits. 

|   
---|---|---  
|  | 

Links to other Sites 

The Website may include links to websites operated by other government agencies, non-profit organizations and private businesses. When the Users link to another site, this Privacy Policy will not apply, however, the Users may be subject to the Privacy Policy of that new website, if one exists. PITB is not in any way responsible for the privacy practices or content of external websites.  |   
---|---|---  
|  | 

Policy Revision and Notification of Changes 

PITB may at any time revise or update this policy without notice. PITB may inform the Users about policy changes through notices on this page containing a version number and date. Any information collected under the current policy will remain subject to these terms. Information collected after any changes take effect will be subject to the revised privacy policy.  |   
---|---|---
